are you ready to
do this tonglen meditation,
that is, the idea is that you need a lot of
preparatory work to
do tonglen well, this is not a simple
meditation, you need a lot
[music]
meditation reflections before
doing this, let's do one like this, get
ready
to comment now Grandfather will lead you
through a short meditation,
this probably means a sage or something like
that, or Grandfather,
you have a greater responsibility,
what about
silence,
if your cell phone is not
turned off yet, then please, turn it off.
So, let's start
this week, I would like to try a
new
meditation, this is 100
I don't know, it's
even more distracting
for me, 10
[music]
works, it's about 6 minutes, so
please, let's
[music]
Yes, just remember where the
exhale, inhale,
now. Think
of some interaction
with someone, for example, yesterday,
with whom you spent But maybe half an hour over the
last few days,
choose one of these
interactions with another person. Where did you spend half an hour, the
person, what did you
want to get from this
interaction, remember.
For example, I spent the last five days with
my wife,
we went to take care of my mother
who had a stroke.
I spent a lot of time with Veronica
I think I was hoping
working on the text sugen it was in the
back of my mind
consciousness when you are with this person what
you
did and thought this time
mode
what you wanted to do What do you think the
other person wanted to do at this time
based on how they acted
what not what he did
[music]
How do you guess what they would like to
do most while
you were together
so that they would enjoy doing while
I think my wife
was focused on helping my mother she
has other people she
helps
because she would like to
concentrate on this at the time
[music]
You can sacrifice what you want to
do and do instead what the
other person wants
but it won't be very sustainable
You probably can't
keep doing it
all the time you have what you want to
do
and that person has what he wants to
do or she
Could there be a third alternative his 10
constantly think the
amount
is if the third choice I would like I know
what my wife would like to do today I
know what I would like to do today
if some
smart
innovative  a creative way
for us both to do what we want
and be together at the same time so that we
also interact and spend the
day together if
what we can do together
what we want Each of us
individually and create a third
possibility of
our relationship our interaction so that somehow
together
with me
so that together we are better off than if we are
separately
if the way that I worked on the student's text
translating this text and
also
served my mother
and
Veronica her
clients we both have equal rights to do
what we want to do if such a very
creative way a
creative way to help everyone to
help each other do what
each of us wants to
do is better than if you did it
alone or at the expense of another person
and this
way of life
also does not do selfishly what he
wants to do from this finds
creative ways
so that everyone gets what they want at the same
time
think about this interaction in the
third choice besides these two choices
somehow so that you can achieve what
both of these people want on the same
day
and what my wife and I did
we set aside time in the morning she likes to walk
along the
California ocean she
walked  for a walk along
the coast and we agreed that
she could collect
for the Day and make a list of things that
she would like to do
today at this time I
[music]
worked on translating students
people
I also have a
function do you
think Could you do something like this
with a person
You will think this is a very creative way a
middle way between doing
what he wants And what you want is
such a middle way so that
each person gets what they want And no
one sacrifices so that everyone's goals are
equally taken into account
these when you can slowly open your eyes
come back stretch
If you are like me then I think that
I remember when I first came to Diamond
Mountain There
were 80 students
We came here to
study the Diamond Way together
they did 7 years of preparation in New York
and we 7 years of the Diamond Way
and we completed this graduation graduation
many did a
three-year retreat And now 200 thousand
students around the world About 15
organizations
[music]
and
requests for my time
have increased by about the same amount
you know
I can't I can't
do
my wife
for each of  200 thousand
what I did
for 80
here some friends from those 80
as before ask me sometimes Can I do it for
an hour
that is
thousands
16 years will be
this is not more intelligent
time management there Time is also
empty
time can also be
increased once
stretched Einstein finished
[music]
proved
the speed of light which deviates
[music]
when
you look at
the past you travel
[music]
truthfully becomes even more You can
directly
observe the past
directly as it happens
and methods cell
connect
those people at the same time this
attitude to the emptiness of
time and space we are in
time we create time
and we
play with space and then we
can
help more people
help each other it is impossible in ordinary
time and space to do what I used to
do it is impossible
to satisfy the
needs of 200 thousand people this
week unless I work
That is, you need
Why did he start
[music]
This means that abbr you need to come to the
present will be otherwise you will never be able to
live early for all living beings
you cannot without an even number of
beings
desire to satisfy
and equal time to share with him Unless you
[music]
Play with this time do something with it
first there must be a desire to
help these hundreds of thousands of people there must
be a desire and this leads you to the fact that you
know such a need is the mother of
invention If you are hungry enough
to serve
because your
ability to help others is
incredible on immeasurable You just
have to
push yourself in the direction